<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-05-05T23:02:17-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Your awesome title</title><subtitle>I see a lot of theatre and sometimes I write about it. I try to see the good in everything.
</subtitle><author><name>Emily Esten</name></author><entry><title type="html">Boycott Esther</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/the%20drake/azuka%20theatre/proscenium%20theatre/2019/05/05/boycott-esther.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Boycott Esther" /><published>2019-05-05T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-05-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/the%20drake/azuka%20theatre/proscenium%20theatre/2019/05/05/boycott-esther</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/the%20drake/azuka%20theatre/proscenium%20theatre/2019/05/05/boycott-esther.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;me, reading the playwright’s bio before the show: bold of her to mention her relationship to The Weinstein Company&lt;/em&gt;
 
&lt;em&gt;me, in the middle of&lt;/em&gt; Boycott Esther &lt;em&gt;: never mind, makes sense&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who among us has not followed the #MeToo movement within entertainment industries since its viral popularity in October 2017? In &lt;em&gt;Boycott Esther&lt;/em&gt;, Esther Lehman (Alison Ormsby) 23-year-old social media influencer finally gets her big break with the possibility of a TV show with the company of media mogul Barry Bloom (Steven Richard). She works with Mary (Alexandra Espinoza) a producer (writer? editor? unclear? I don’t know media) at Bloom’s company to perfect her pilot script. She talks regularly to her parents, a friend, an agent (all done through video or audio), and posting regularly to her Instagram and Twitter accounts along the way. But when Bloom faces a similar scandal to Weinstein and Cosby - as he explicitly references  - Esther’s career is tied too closely to Bloom’s orbit. Esther, who presents herself as feminist and empowered and (insert some other word than woke), attempts to keep both that identity and the one tied to Bloom’s horrible behavior in order to move forward with her career. How she deals with it  - from her relationship to Bloom and to Mary, as well as her Internet followers and family - take up the latter half of the show.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite its difficult topic, the show is &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; funny. Even when the moment is serious, the audience is reacting at the awkwardness of the situation. And there are larger themes at work here. Our leading ladies are not the explicit victims of #MeToo, but also harmed by Bloom’s horrible work - it’s about how are careers are tied to our ethics. It is a show about feminism, both performative and direct-action-oriented, as Mary brings up in her monologue towards the end of the show. Social media shaming and Internet success is a part of this, too, though it seems less of interest when so many other shows have tackled that story. It fuels the story without ever being the center of attention - and in some ways, seeing this happen to this influencer in a career context whose vested interest in her feminist identity made it more palatable than another show about cyberbullying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rishard and Espinoza in their recorded and onstage work, but I mostly want to applaud Ormsby. She is fantastic in the titular role - for most of the show, she’s the only physical presence the audience views. She plays it entirely naturally - even the knowing smile she gives as the lights come up for final bows seems in character still. Most of the show takes place in Esther’s bedroom (or true-to-life Brooklyn studio apartment), and Ormsby makes even mindless scrolling captivating to watch. Though the time passes incredibly quickly us for us as an audience, we do get to see some aging and maturity (or lack thereof) in the character. Her transformation from 23-year-old empowered Internet-Esther, the one who talks to her parents like she talks to Twitter to a scared and confused 25-year-old in a Brooklyn coffee shop occurs almost instantaneously, and not a second is lost. I truly cannot wait to see her in another production.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, this performance is also a celebration of Maura Krause, who has crafted a show that can function in all these dimensions. Krause’s direction not only extends to the physical space of the stage, but to the virtual connections with video, lighting, and sound. The technology at play here is of equal importance to the cast, and it’s without a doubt the best uses I’ve seen of all three media so far this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I usually see endings coming, but I completely missed this one and found myself trying to catch up in the final scene. I can’t reveal it without explaining many of the hints and conversation the show goes through - it is both inside joke and explanation of much of what comes before it. Which is truly the best kind of final scene, isn’t it? Acker’s book is truly fantastic for this moment - I wonder what it will look like two or three years down the line, or even a decade or two. While the show is rooted in its technology and the social media on which it depends (in addition to the cultural moment), it’s also very much of a story of our internet selves and personalities. As one character notes, how will our AI treat us if this is how we treat ourselves online? And what does our feminism mean for ourselves and others in the workplace if we don’t think about the humanity behind our words?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Emily Esten</name></author><summary type="html">me, reading the playwright’s bio before the show: bold of her to mention her relationship to The Weinstein Company   me, in the middle of Boycott Esther : never mind, makes sense</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Waiting for Lefty</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/pilot%20projects/ignoble%20artists/clifford%20odets/2019/05/04/waiting-for-lefty.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Waiting for Lefty" /><published>2019-05-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-05-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/pilot%20projects/ignoble%20artists/clifford%20odets/2019/05/04/waiting-for-lefty</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/pilot%20projects/ignoble%20artists/clifford%20odets/2019/05/04/waiting-for-lefty.html">&lt;p&gt;Funny how you can watch a show and, with a few minor tweaks, it could still fit pretty well today. The performers made really great use of such a small space - the show is intimate by nature, and making the audience a part of the union meeting made total sense. Can’t wait for another Ignoble Artists production - the audience interaction and post-show discussion were well done.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Emily Esten</name></author><summary type="html">Funny how you can watch a show and, with a few minor tweaks, it could still fit pretty well today. The performers made really great use of such a small space - the show is intimate by nature, and making the audience a part of the union meeting made total sense. Can’t wait for another Ignoble Artists production - the audience interaction and post-show discussion were well done.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Among the Dead</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/hansol%20jung/theatre%20exile/2019/05/03/among-the-dead.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Among the Dead" /><published>2019-05-03T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-05-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/hansol%20jung/theatre%20exile/2019/05/03/among-the-dead</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/hansol%20jung/theatre%20exile/2019/05/03/among-the-dead.html">&lt;p&gt;I only learned about the comfort women of WWII earlier this year, which I think was helpful in preparing for what this story was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The inclusion of Jesus in this story was something I thought would be annoying and tiresome, but I think it was fitting. (Cathy Simpson is hilarious when needed, and intense at the most important monologue.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish the student riots took more of a place in the story, instead of just background noise.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Emily Esten</name></author><summary type="html">I only learned about the comfort women of WWII earlier this year, which I think was helpful in preparing for what this story was.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">La Boheme</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/opera%20philadelphia/opera/academy%20of%20music/puccini/2019/04/26/la-boheme.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="La Boheme" /><published>2019-04-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-04-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/opera%20philadelphia/opera/academy%20of%20music/puccini/2019/04/26/la-boheme</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/opera%20philadelphia/opera/academy%20of%20music/puccini/2019/04/26/la-boheme.html">&lt;p&gt;Shout to the two women behind me who pointed out all the similarities to &lt;em&gt;RENT&lt;/em&gt; (“Light My Candle” is almost the exact same) and the couple beside me who gave accurate reviews of the show. The set uses Impressionist art, which I’ve seen employed better elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably going to avoid the opera in the future, though the orchestra is amazing.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Emily Esten</name></author><summary type="html">Shout to the two women behind me who pointed out all the similarities to RENT (“Light My Candle” is almost the exact same) and the couple beside me who gave accurate reviews of the show. The set uses Impressionist art, which I’ve seen employed better elsewhere.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Cradle Will Rock</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/marc%20blitzstein/classic%20stage%20company/lynn%20f.%20angelson%20theater/2019/04/14/the-cradle-will-rock.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Cradle Will Rock" /><published>2019-04-14T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-04-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/marc%20blitzstein/classic%20stage%20company/lynn%20f.%20angelson%20theater/2019/04/14/the-cradle-will-rock</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/marc%20blitzstein/classic%20stage%20company/lynn%20f.%20angelson%20theater/2019/04/14/the-cradle-will-rock.html">&lt;p&gt;In the olden days, nobody was subtle. Blitzstein sure wasn’t. The vignettes are well done - Rema Webb’s “Joe Worker” was the best, truly brining the house down. Tony Yazbeck is great, though I wish he didn’t have to play two roles (I was confused about which character he was supposed to be.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CSC stopped doing playbills, which isn’t cool. Cool set with the oil drums and wires up on the ceiling. (I wanted to take a picture, but could not.) Also, I learned that Marc Blitzstein was from Philadelphia, so I’ll ave to go looking for his historical marker at 4th and Pine.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Emily Esten</name></author><summary type="html">In the olden days, nobody was subtle. Blitzstein sure wasn’t. The vignettes are well done - Rema Webb’s “Joe Worker” was the best, truly brining the house down. Tony Yazbeck is great, though I wish he didn’t have to play two roles (I was confused about which character he was supposed to be.)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Click</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/simpatico%20theatre/the%20louis%20bluver%20theatre/the%20drake/2019/04/10/click.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Click" /><published>2019-04-10T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-04-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/simpatico%20theatre/the%20louis%20bluver%20theatre/the%20drake/2019/04/10/click</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/simpatico%20theatre/the%20louis%20bluver%20theatre/the%20drake/2019/04/10/click.html">&lt;p&gt;The story of this show is still bugging me. I don’t get Fresh’s hypocritical art - using tragedy and horror to set the stage when it’s part of the reason she (spoiler) entered into this predicament in the first life. Teh technological leaps are very cool here - and well served - but the story doesn’t work for me.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Emily Esten</name></author><summary type="html">The story of this show is still bugging me. I don’t get Fresh’s hypocritical art - using tragedy and horror to set the stage when it’s part of the reason she (spoiler) entered into this predicament in the first life. Teh technological leaps are very cool here - and well served - but the story doesn’t work for me.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">King Lear</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/quintessence%20theatre%20group/the%20sedgwick%20theatre/shakespeare/2019/04/06/king-lear.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="King Lear" /><published>2019-04-06T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-04-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/quintessence%20theatre%20group/the%20sedgwick%20theatre/shakespeare/2019/04/06/king-lear</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/quintessence%20theatre%20group/the%20sedgwick%20theatre/shakespeare/2019/04/06/king-lear.html">&lt;p&gt;Couldn’t afford to see Glenda Jackson’s &lt;em&gt;King Lear&lt;/em&gt;, took a trip up to Mount Airy to see this instead. Good choice! Appreciated the foyer (throne room) and the black box (everything else). Musical cues were off-putting. Shout out to Anita Holland, who makes Regan truly terrifying.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Emily Esten</name></author><summary type="html">Couldn’t afford to see Glenda Jackson’s King Lear, took a trip up to Mount Airy to see this instead. Good choice! Appreciated the foyer (throne room) and the black box (everything else). Musical cues were off-putting. Shout out to Anita Holland, who makes Regan truly terrifying.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Heartland</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/interact%20theatre%20company/the%20drake/proscenium%20theater/2019/04/02/heartland.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Heartland" /><published>2019-04-02T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-04-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/interact%20theatre%20company/the%20drake/proscenium%20theater/2019/04/02/heartland</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/interact%20theatre%20company/the%20drake/proscenium%20theater/2019/04/02/heartland.html">&lt;p&gt;It’s fine. Predictable once you figured it out, and I’m not sure what I gained from seeing the story play out this way. Liked the set though. And would love to see Yousof Sultani in another show.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Emily Esten</name></author><summary type="html">It’s fine. Predictable once you figured it out, and I’m not sure what I gained from seeing the story play out this way. Liked the set though. And would love to see Yousof Sultani in another show.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Miss Saigon</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/broadway%20philadelphia/kimmel%20center/academy%20of%20music/2019/03/30/miss-saigon.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Miss Saigon" /><published>2019-03-30T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-03-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/broadway%20philadelphia/kimmel%20center/academy%20of%20music/2019/03/30/miss-saigon</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/broadway%20philadelphia/kimmel%20center/academy%20of%20music/2019/03/30/miss-saigon.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dontbuymiss-saigon.com/&quot;&gt;Don’t see Miss Saigon&lt;/a&gt;. Really regret seeing this, as the book itself is as horrible as everyone told me. I did cry twice - “The Fall of Saigon” because the US sucks, and the “Finale” because even though you know it’s coming it’s incredibly jarring. (Side note, but how did my high school do this show in 2018???)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Score is pretty though, and the voices carried all the way to my seat in the very top balcony.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Emily Esten</name></author><summary type="html">Don’t see Miss Saigon. Really regret seeing this, as the book itself is as horrible as everyone told me. I did cry twice - “The Fall of Saigon” because the US sucks, and the “Finale” because even though you know it’s coming it’s incredibly jarring. (Side note, but how did my high school do this show in 2018???)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How To Catch Creation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/philadelphia%20theatre%20company/suzanne%20roberts%20theatre/2019/03/22/how-to-catch-creation.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How To Catch Creation" /><published>2019-03-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-03-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/philadelphia%20theatre%20company/suzanne%20roberts%20theatre/2019/03/22/how-to-catch-creation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/philadelphia%20theatre%20company/suzanne%20roberts%20theatre/2019/03/22/how-to-catch-creation.html">&lt;p&gt;(written months later)
I usually recommend reading the notes in the playbill before the show, but I’m going to suggest you don’t here. The writer’s note doesn’t spoil anything per se, but if you read it at the beginning and then think about it as the show’s direction becomes clear, it does. And I wonder if the show would’ve felt more - something - if I hadn’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The couple in front of me left at intermission. “The show has no direction,” said one man. “No direction,” said the other. “You want to head out?” said the first. I, too, was lost at intermission. The three stories - Stokes and Riley, a young couple in their 20s figuring out their career passions; Griffin and Tammy, friends in their 40s figuring out their relationships; Natalie and Gina, somewhere in the 1960s exploring their relationship to each other - didn’t seem to connect organically. Griffin felt like the heart of the show, and the other scenes tacked on around him, to make it work. I was interested, invested, but unsure. Why were the scenes of the two romantic couples juxtaposed? Why are we getting references to Tammy’s history? What do we get from these&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second act, though, makes its direction very clear from the first scene. I found myself wincing through much of the second act, hoping the show wouldn’t take the route I expected. (For the most part, it does.) The passage of time here is wildly unclear - those might be slips of the tongue by the actors, but does the second act happen over weeks? Months? The relationships seems wildly engaged and deep for such short periods of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Griffin here is the main character, it feels - but his story falls away fairly quickly. He helps move everyone else along, but his story doesn’t really get resolved at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The title comes from one of GK Marchet’s poems, which Griffin quotes at length late into the second act. How to Catch Creation is about creation in three forms. The first, as we learn at the start, is the creation of a child - the agony &amp;amp; expectations involved in Griffin’s unique struggles as an independent parent. What does it mean to be a parent? How do we understand that choice? What’s involved?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second, the parallels of which are made far too often in the first act to be inconspicuous, is the creation of art. Stokes’ portraits as well as his novel; Riley’s music and possible graphic design(?); Tammy’s work as an artist; Gina’s novel; Natalie’s clothing. (Supposedly Griffin’s as well, though we don’t see that until much later on.) The final one is the creation of relationships -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bay Area takes on a role as a character here, too. The Golden Gate Bridge takes center stage, the set moving around it in concentric circles to take us from place to place. I like it - the sky above us changing to reflect our feelings and mood, the reminder of this space as their home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;+1 to the use of music &amp;amp; sound here. The cues were pretty on point for a first preview, and the setting sounds never seemed too out of place but always in the background.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generally, I found myself smiling for a good part of the show. We’re supposed to, I think. Again, there’s a moment here where Tammy and Griffin reach a breaking point - a crucial fight - and the audience is laughing. Are we supposed to laugh? I mean, it’s understandably funny, her frustration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The actors are great - Tammy especially, though the character is all over the place. I found myself drawn to Nayib Felix’s Stokes. I’d love to see Griffin’s do more - the key moments he has are great, but the show generally doesn’t let him do much more. Everything we’re given about him comes from being told who he is, rather than showing.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Emily Esten</name></author><summary type="html">(written months later) I usually recommend reading the notes in the playbill before the show, but I’m going to suggest you don’t here. The writer’s note doesn’t spoil anything per se, but if you read it at the beginning and then think about it as the show’s direction becomes clear, it does. And I wonder if the show would’ve felt more - something - if I hadn’t.</summary></entry></feed>