<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-06-21T14:45:54-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Gods of the theatre, smile on us.</title><subtitle>I see a lot of theatre and sometimes I write about it. I try to see the good in everything.
</subtitle><author><name>Emily Esten</name></author><entry><title type="html">Hadestown</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/05/26/hadestown" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hadestown" /><published>2019-05-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-05-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/05/26/hadestown</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/05/26/hadestown">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Who stands in the garden with nothing to lose, singing:
La la la la la la la…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the third Greek-myth-inspired performance I’ve seen this year. Come see what the world could be - and what it is - in more ways than one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anaïs Mitchell’s folk opera weaves together two related Greek myths into one, this time adapted for a Depression-era, New Orleans-inspired jazz period. Orpheus (Reeve Carney) and Eurydice (Eve Noblezada) are our leads: the former is a musician working on his song, the latter a young woman who has experienced the harshness of the world. They quickly fall hopelessly for each other, but love fares poorly in the cold, hungry world without summer. In the background, Hades (Patrick Page) and Persephone (Amber Gray), leaders of the underworld, work through marital strife and the decline of their relationship. For those who know these characters and myths in their Greek origins, they continue to be stories of love, passion, and human spirit, with a newfound backdrop of survival. Hermes (Andre De Shields), god of boundaries and conductor of souls to the afterlife, narrates us&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main cast in its entirety are wonderfully chosen - Page’s Hades is not villainous but a man struggling with power and doubt; Carney’s Orpheus is every bit the poor boy Hermes describes him as; De Shields is a natural storyteller from his first “Aight?”; Noblezada makes me want to cry with her every note. But the real star is Amber Gray as Persephone, who is delight from the moment we see her in the jazz club balcony, bringing joy to her “Livin’ It Up on Top” and sultry frustration to “Our Lady of the Underground.” Of all these characters, hers feels the most developed and empowered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was also particularly taken with the ensemble. How do five members make a stage feel so full, so big? We are constantly reminded of Hades’ power and children building the wall, and somehow these five can (It helps that the stage is also filled with the orchestra.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The underworld set, complete with its flashing lights and lanterns is probably the darkest one I have ever seen on stage - and yet, it works. You can see everything, the lighting makes it so that Hades is shrouded when he needs to be and the underworld dark without being too dark to see. Orpheus’s descent, complete with the full foundry opening to the audience, is awe-inspiring for all of us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many plot questions that still remain for me, and the transition to sung-through musical to some minor book scenes almost makes it weaker. There were moments that I didn’t necessarily agree with structure or direction, but found myself pleasantly surprised with how things worked out in its storytelling. I found myself whispering “blackout, blackout, blackout” at the moment &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; thought would be the ending, and was confused by what the message when it actually ends. If someone wants to explain that to me, I’d appreciate it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-lot-of-stray-observations&quot;&gt;(a lot of) Stray Observations:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cause of Death: Patrick Page saying “I missed you.” I knew his voice was low, but DAMN.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are lots of reviews complaining about Reeve Carney’s Orpheus, and I don’t necessarily disagree. I like the innocent quality he brings to the role, making Orpheus the naïve poor boy he is built up to be, and bringing that to each song (and &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; song). I found the falsetto tough to handle at first but it grew on me. (Side note, but if I had to choose a role I would want to be in this show, it’d be Orpheus.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I gasped a bunch.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Microphones??? MICROPHONES????&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Everyone mentions the &lt;em&gt;RENT&lt;/em&gt; similarities with Mimi/Eurydice &amp;amp; Roger/Orpheus - they’re not wrong.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;At the stage door, you get a (fake) carnation! It’s a cute souvenir.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SHOUT OUT TO THE BAND (especially the trombonist.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The four women in front of me were a riot, and I request them to be at every Broadway show I see from now on. My favorite line: “I can’t wait to go to hell because hell slaps. Hell absolutely slaps.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What was this like in the round??? I almost wish they had kept it that way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Emily Esten</name></author><category term="Broadway" /><category term="Walter Kerr Theatre" /><summary type="html">Who stands in the garden with nothing to lose, singing: La la la la la la la…</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The God Project</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/05/18/the-god-project" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The God Project" /><published>2019-05-18T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-05-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/05/18/the-god-project</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/05/18/the-god-project">&lt;p&gt;Two former pastor’s kids - Sheila (Jennifer Childs) and Drew (Sean Close) - work the night shift at a Swedish furniture store. Sheila is a faithful paladin without her path, still ultimately committed to her Christian. Drew, on the other hand, is openly resentful of his upbringing. He is also without a path, after getting kicked out of his band and stuck performing at local open-mic performances. And then there’s Val (Joliet Harris), the God (or god-like) omniscient and omnipresent manager for the night shift. Sheila and Drew learn to work together and find themselves with (or without) faith to guide them onto a new path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Childs and Drew cowrote and costar in this show. Childs is an absolute delight to watch, and makes the stereotypical Christian role one who all want to root for from early on. I can’t imagine how difficult it is for Close not to break character. This show is funny - Childs and Close have a great dynamic, and for anyone familiar with the Church or the path to finding yourself, there’s something admirable here. For a night out, the show was enjoyable as a story more about faith and spirituality than about Christianity itself.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Emily Esten</name></author><category term="1812 Productions" /><category term="Plays &amp; Players Theatre" /><summary type="html">Two former pastor’s kids - Sheila (Jennifer Childs) and Drew (Sean Close) - work the night shift at a Swedish furniture store. Sheila is a faithful paladin without her path, still ultimately committed to her Christian. Drew, on the other hand, is openly resentful of his upbringing. He is also without a path, after getting kicked out of his band and stuck performing at local open-mic performances. And then there’s Val (Joliet Harris), the God (or god-like) omniscient and omnipresent manager for the night shift. Sheila and Drew learn to work together and find themselves with (or without) faith to guide them onto a new path.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Untitled</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/05/08/untitled" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Untitled" /><published>2019-05-08T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-05-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/05/08/untitled</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/05/08/untitled">&lt;p&gt;Twin brothers, born on Nigerian Independence Day, grown up on two different sides of the country’s life. X, left nameless on the night of his naming, grows up in Nigeria and relays his twenty-five years to the audience. Y, given a name though never to us, grows up a Nigerian-born Londoner. Keith Illidge masterfully plays both brothers, in addition to 11 different characters throughout the show, each one a distinct personality, movement, and voice. For a place of magic and mythology, the performance makes Nigeria - both young and old, new and same, come alive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The differences between X and Y are distinct - though both storytellers, X’s lore mirrors Nigerian traditions and community gatherings; Y’s poetry means his stories move softly and quickly, and even its nervous moments as though it is being sputtered out. But do not mistake the show’s premise - this is X’s story first and foremost. Y has a developed story, but it is about returning to Nigeria, returning to his brother. While other reviews thinks this second story suffers, I think it is ultimately successful and worth the diversion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the set! The set! THE SET! This is Marie Laster’s first solo professional production, and it is amazing how a show so intimate feels so large on this stage. The tree’s placement takes over all. The woodchips are so effective (reminding me a lot of the floor at Egoli)! Laster’s background in architecture seems like a natural fit, and it’s helping me figure out more of what makes a set successful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I couldn’t help but jump to Teju Cole’s work for Y’s half - returning to Lagos reminded me so much of reading &lt;em&gt;Open City&lt;/em&gt;. Or even Binyavanga Wainana’s &lt;em&gt;One Day I Will Write About This Place&lt;/em&gt; for X, though I haven’t read his work in quite a long time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;## Notes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I really appreciated the talk-back (takeaway) here with Artistic Director Tom Reing, set designer Marie Laster, actor Keith Illidge, and dramaturg Adrena Williams. Their willingness to talk through the process of a building a show, their responsibilities in its creation, and their reflections on it now helped the audience.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SOUND! Daniel Ison’s sound is very important here, and its movement around the stage is awesome.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Emily Esten</name></author><category term="The Drake" /><category term="Inis Nua Theatre Company" /><category term="Louis Bluver Theater" /><summary type="html">Twin brothers, born on Nigerian Independence Day, grown up on two different sides of the country’s life. X, left nameless on the night of his naming, grows up in Nigeria and relays his twenty-five years to the audience. Y, given a name though never to us, grows up a Nigerian-born Londoner. Keith Illidge masterfully plays both brothers, in addition to 11 different characters throughout the show, each one a distinct personality, movement, and voice. For a place of magic and mythology, the performance makes Nigeria - both young and old, new and same, come alive.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Boycott Esther</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/05/05/boycott-esther" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Boycott Esther" /><published>2019-05-05T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-05-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/05/05/boycott-esther</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/05/05/boycott-esther">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;me, reading the playwright’s bio before the show: bold of her to mention her relationship to The Weinstein Company&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;me, in the middle of&lt;/em&gt; Boycott Esther &lt;em&gt;: never mind, makes sense&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who among us has not followed the #MeToo movement within entertainment industries since its viral popularity in October 2017? In &lt;em&gt;Boycott Esther&lt;/em&gt;, Esther Lehman (Alison Ormsby) 23-year-old social media influencer finally gets her big break with the possibility of a TV show with the company of media mogul Barry Bloom (Steven Richard). She works with Mary (Alexandra Espinoza) a producer (writer? editor? unclear? I don’t know media) at Bloom’s company to perfect her pilot script. She talks regularly to her parents, a friend, an agent (all done through video or audio), and posting regularly to her Instagram and Twitter accounts along the way. But when Bloom faces a similar scandal to Weinstein and Cosby - as he explicitly references  - Esther’s career is tied too closely to Bloom’s orbit. Esther, who presents herself as feminist and empowered and (insert some other word than woke), attempts to keep both that identity and the one tied to Bloom’s horrible behavior in order to move forward with her career. How she deals with it  - from her relationship to Bloom and to Mary, as well as her Internet followers and family - take up the latter half of the show.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite its difficult topic, the show is &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; funny. Even when the moment is serious, the audience is reacting at the awkwardness of the situation. And there are larger themes at work here. Our leading ladies are not the explicit victims of #MeToo, but also harmed by Bloom’s horrible work - it’s about how are careers are tied to our ethics. It is a show about feminism, both performative and direct-action-oriented, as Mary brings up in her monologue towards the end of the show. Social media shaming and Internet success is a part of this, too, though it seems less of interest when so many other shows have tackled that story. It fuels the story without ever being the center of attention - and in some ways, seeing this happen to this influencer in a career context whose vested interest in her feminist identity made it more palatable than another show about cyberbullying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rishard and Espinoza in their recorded and onstage work, but I mostly want to applaud Ormsby. She is fantastic in the titular role - for most of the show, she’s the only physical presence the audience views. She plays it entirely naturally - even the knowing smile she gives as the lights come up for final bows seems in character still. Most of the show takes place in Esther’s bedroom (or true-to-life Brooklyn studio apartment), and Ormsby makes even mindless scrolling captivating to watch. Though the time passes incredibly quickly us for us as an audience, we do get to see some aging and maturity (or lack thereof) in the character. Her transformation from 23-year-old empowered Internet-Esther, the one who talks to her parents like she talks to Twitter to a scared and confused 25-year-old in a Brooklyn coffee shop occurs almost instantaneously, and not a second is lost. I truly cannot wait to see her in another production.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, this performance is also a celebration of Maura Krause, who has crafted a show that can function in all these dimensions. Krause’s direction not only extends to the physical space of the stage, but to the virtual connections with video, lighting, and sound. The technology at play here is of equal importance to the cast, and it’s without a doubt the best uses I’ve seen of all three media so far this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I usually see endings coming, but I completely missed this one and found myself trying to catch up in the final scene. I can’t reveal it without explaining many of the hints and conversation the show goes through - it is both inside joke and explanation of much of what comes before it. Which is truly the best kind of final scene, isn’t it? Acker’s book is truly fantastic for this moment - I wonder what it will look like two or three years down the line, or even a decade or two. While the show is rooted in its technology and the social media on which it depends (in addition to the cultural moment), it’s also very much of a story of our internet selves and personalities. As one character notes, how will our AI treat us if this is how we treat ourselves online? And what does our feminism mean for ourselves and others in the workplace if we don’t think about the humanity behind our words?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Emily Esten</name></author><category term="The Drake" /><category term="Azuka Theatre" /><category term="Proscenium Theatre" /><summary type="html">me, reading the playwright’s bio before the show: bold of her to mention her relationship to The Weinstein Company me, in the middle of Boycott Esther : never mind, makes sense</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Waiting for Lefty</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/05/04/waiting-for-lefty" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Waiting for Lefty" /><published>2019-05-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-05-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/05/04/waiting-for-lefty</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/05/04/waiting-for-lefty">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We’re reds if because we wanna strike, then we take over their salute, too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Funny how you can watch a show and, with a few minor tweaks, it could still fit pretty well today. Its closing night just a few days before the 2019 rideshare strikes/rallies, &lt;em&gt;Waiting for Lefty&lt;/em&gt; is perfect for an audience whose knowledge of strikes is severely lacking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented as a series of vignettes, the show hinges on a union debate of whether to strike. But we don’t just see members of the cab drivers union during the debate - we see a husband and wife argue over being able to survive another day with the racketeers looming in the background; a lab assistant standing up to his own boss; a boyfriend and girlfriend trying to make a future when job uncertainty is the only thing that is certain; and a doctor frustration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The performers made really great use of such a small space - the show is intimate by nature, and making the audience a part of the union meeting made total sense. In some ways, I found this to be a great companion to the  &lt;em&gt;The Cradle Will Rock&lt;/em&gt;. The former uses parody to encourage you and see all the problems of capitalism within corruption and corporate greed; this uses historical inspiration to note how much exists even within these smaller situations on a day-to-day basis, from the perspective of the workers. Both are pro-union agitprop structured around these vignettes, but &lt;em&gt;Cradle&lt;/em&gt; seems palatable to a larger audience while &lt;em&gt;Waiting for Lefty&lt;/em&gt; hinges on a strike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I truly can’t wait for another Ignoble Artists production. The audience interaction and post-show discussion were well done.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Emily Esten</name></author><category term="Pilot Projects" /><category term="Ignoble Artists" /><category term="Clifford Odets" /><summary type="html">We’re reds if because we wanna strike, then we take over their salute, too!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Among the Dead</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/05/03/among-the-dead" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Among the Dead" /><published>2019-05-03T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-05-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/05/03/among-the-dead</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/05/03/among-the-dead">&lt;p&gt;Among the Dead is a dark comedy about a family broken apart by betrayed promises, and finding each other again through SPAM, journals, and Jesus. Mostly Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1945, Luke (James Kern), an American soldier leaves the jungles of Myanmar with baby Ana after pleas from her mother - Number Four (Claris Park). In 1975, Ana (Bi Jean Ngo), fulfilling a last wish of her recently-deceased (unclear, but he is dead?) father, arrives in Seoul with his ashes. Upon arrival, Ana is presented with her father’s journal of his time during the war. We follow them both forward from those moments - Ana as she learns what her estranged father did during this time, switching between the role of her mother and herself; Number Four only from opening moment After, and her struggle to survive. Jesus (Cathy Simpson) functions as narrator, guide to the characters, and NPCs in between.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The audience knows the interconnectedness of the two stories throughout - we know how the journal ends in the opening scene. And the characters know of their connection, too, somewhat. In spite of that predictability, the details have you captivated. We know &lt;em&gt;an&lt;/em&gt; ending point, but not necessarily &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; ending point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I only learned about the comfort women of WWII earlier this year, which I think was helpful in preparing for what this story would address. I thought both the book and production handle the graphic nature of their histories well - it is only seen once, as a flashback, and the horror is there is inflicted as both generational and of the moment. It is discussed, and never hidden - it is clear to Number Four knows how she has been treated, and the soldier figures it out if never saying it explicitly, and never explicitly placing blame on her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ngo and Park are wonderful in their time-warping depictions of Number Four- or, if we want to get technical, their depictions of the same person albeit through different eyes. Ana looks older, feels older, though she’s likely the same image. And it’s also how Luke likely saw Ana growing up. The actors are great. Park is truly a transformative actor - having seen them earlier this year in &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;BOB: A Life in Five Acts&lt;/a&gt;, they were almost unrecognizable here in a dramatic role. Bi Jean Ngo plays daughter-as-mother in such a way that you never forget this is &lt;em&gt;Luke&lt;/em&gt;’s interpretation of Number Four, and her Ana is everything Park is in playing her mother even with the slightest mannerisms. In the scene which takes place on the bridge, they are mirror, identical but not quite, and it is &lt;em&gt;good.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The inclusion of Jesus in this story was something I thought would be annoying and tiresome, but I think it was fitting. Cathy Simpson is hilarious when needed, and intense at her most important monologue. I would want to watch it with a different actor, only to see how good Simpson makes it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a story about women, so I’m surprised in myself for feeling slightly frustrated by the lack of development for Luke. His story seems unlike others of the period - becoming a career man, essentially abandoning his daughter - but there are glimpses of another person he could have been. Another life. We watch him make wrong choice after wrong choice within the show, and feel slighted in that we only see him make one right one. Or maybe two, depending on how you look at it. And maybe I’m asking for the wrong question - maybe I’m looking to redeem Luke in a way that he cannot be by own standards, after doing something so incredibly horrific early on that I found in-character and yet ruins the character. We never see take ownership of his actions other than to feel guilt (if even that? if even about the wrong things?) And for him to continually inflict this trauma onto Ana and Number Four makes the (spoiler) mother-daughter reunion of the finale an even sadder one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having seen Miss Saigon in March, the comparisons immediately jumped out of me. This show probably won’t get as much of an audience, which is a shame. This, sans orchestrations, is clearly the better show, even though they are about two different wars and cultures. They are both about women’s bodily autonomy (or lack thereof), about generational trauma from war, and family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;other-notes&quot;&gt;Other notes:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I wish the student riots took more of a place in the story, instead of just background noise. While there was some information included in the program about Korea’s history and the timing of the riots, I want to know more of why Jung chose to specify that setting. Am I missing something here of the connections of the protests with the war itself?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Love when they split the audience on either side of the stage, because I get to watch other people’s reactions as they’re figuring out the story.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SET! SOUND! Makes it feel fully even when sparse.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Emily Esten</name></author><category term="Hansol Jung" /><category term="Theatre Exile" /><summary type="html">Among the Dead is a dark comedy about a family broken apart by betrayed promises, and finding each other again through SPAM, journals, and Jesus. Mostly Jesus.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">La Boheme</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/04/26/la-boheme" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="La Boheme" /><published>2019-04-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-04-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/04/26/la-boheme</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/04/26/la-boheme">&lt;p&gt;Shout to the two women behind me who pointed out all the similarities to &lt;em&gt;RENT&lt;/em&gt; (“Light My Candle” is almost the exact same) and the couple beside me who gave accurate reviews of the show. The set uses Impressionist art, which I’ve seen employed better elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably going to avoid the opera in the future, though the orchestra is amazing.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Emily Esten</name></author><category term="Opera Philadelphia" /><category term="Opera" /><category term="Academy of Music" /><category term="Puccini" /><summary type="html">Shout to the two women behind me who pointed out all the similarities to RENT (“Light My Candle” is almost the exact same) and the couple beside me who gave accurate reviews of the show. The set uses Impressionist art, which I’ve seen employed better elsewhere.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Cradle Will Rock</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/04/14/the-cradle-will-rock" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Cradle Will Rock" /><published>2019-04-14T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-04-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/04/14/the-cradle-will-rock</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/04/14/the-cradle-will-rock">&lt;p&gt;In the olden days, nobody was subtle. Blitzstein sure wasn’t. The vignettes are well done - Rema Webb’s “Joe Worker” was the best, truly brining the house down. Tony Yazbeck is great, though I wish he didn’t have to play two roles (I was confused about which character he was supposed to be.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CSC stopped doing playbills, which isn’t cool. Cool set with the oil drums and wires up on the ceiling. (I wanted to take a picture, but could not.) Also, I learned that Marc Blitzstein was from Philadelphia, so I’ll ave to go looking for his historical marker at 4th and Pine.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Emily Esten</name></author><category term="Marc Blitzstein" /><category term="Classic Stage Company" /><category term="Lynn F. Angelson Theater" /><summary type="html">In the olden days, nobody was subtle. Blitzstein sure wasn’t. The vignettes are well done - Rema Webb’s “Joe Worker” was the best, truly brining the house down. Tony Yazbeck is great, though I wish he didn’t have to play two roles (I was confused about which character he was supposed to be.)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Click</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/04/10/click" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Click" /><published>2019-04-10T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-04-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/04/10/click</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/04/10/click">&lt;p&gt;The story of this show is still bugging me. I don’t get Fresh’s hypocritical art - using tragedy and horror to set the stage when it’s part of the reason she (spoiler) entered into this predicament in the first life. Teh technological leaps are very cool here - and well served - but the story doesn’t work for me.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Emily Esten</name></author><category term="Simpatico Theatre" /><category term="The Louis Bluver Theatre" /><category term="The Drake" /><summary type="html">The story of this show is still bugging me. I don’t get Fresh’s hypocritical art - using tragedy and horror to set the stage when it’s part of the reason she (spoiler) entered into this predicament in the first life. Teh technological leaps are very cool here - and well served - but the story doesn’t work for me.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">King Lear</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/04/06/king-lear" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="King Lear" /><published>2019-04-06T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-04-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/04/06/king-lear</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/04/06/king-lear">&lt;p&gt;Couldn’t afford to see Glenda Jackson’s &lt;em&gt;King Lear&lt;/em&gt;, took a trip up to Mount Airy to see this instead. Good choice! Appreciated the foyer (throne room) and the black box (everything else). Musical cues were off-putting. Shout out to Anita Holland, who makes Regan truly terrifying.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Emily Esten</name></author><category term="Quintessence Theatre Group" /><category term="The Sedgwick Theatre" /><category term="Shakespeare" /><summary type="html">Couldn’t afford to see Glenda Jackson’s King Lear, took a trip up to Mount Airy to see this instead. Good choice! Appreciated the foyer (throne room) and the black box (everything else). Musical cues were off-putting. Shout out to Anita Holland, who makes Regan truly terrifying.</summary></entry></feed>